Guide to the Benét Family Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Benét Family Collection
1912-1979
YCAL MSS 1108
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
8.89
22 boxes
Benét Family
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Acquired by gift and purchase, 1941-1996. For more information consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 22: Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
Benét family
Brigadier General S. V. (Stephen Vincent) Benét was born 22 January 1827 in St. Augustine, Florida. He studied at Hallowell's school in Alexandria, Virginia and then at the University of Georgia and the United States Military Academy, where he graduated in 1849. He was appointed to the Ordnance Corps, and served at the Watervliet Arsenal, at Washington, at Frankford Arsenal, again at Washington, and then at the St. Louis Arsenal. In 1859 he became Assistant Professor of Geography, History, and Ethics at West Point, and from 1861 until 1864 was instructor of Ordnance and the Science of Gunnery. From 1865 until 1869 he was in command of Frankford arsenal. In 1869 he became Assistant to the Chief of Ordnance, and in 1874 he succeeded to Chief of Ordnance with the rank of Brigadier General. He translated Jomini's " Political and Military History of the Campaign of Waterloo" (New York, 1853) and he is the author of a treatise on "Military Law and the Practice of Courts-Martial" (1862) and "Electro-Ballistic Machines and the Schultze Chronoscope" (1866).
He married Laura Amanda Walker and together they had two sons, James Walker Benét and Laurence Vincent Benét.
James Walker Benét (1857-1928), a Colonel in the U.S. Army, was born 16 July, 1857 in Richmond, Kentucky. He graduated from West Point Academy in 1880 and went on to serve most of his military career in the Army Ordnance Department. From 1890 until his retirement in 1921, he served at the Frankford Arsenal, Philadelphia (1890-1984); Bethlehem Iron Works, South Bethlehem, Pennsylvania (1894-1898); Ordnance Headquarters, Buffalo, New York (1898-1899); Watervliet Arsenal, New York (1904-1905, 1919-1921); Rock Island Arsenal, Illinois (1904-1905), Benicia Arsenal, California (1905-1911), and Augusta Arsenal, Georgia (1911-1918).
James Walker Benét married Frances Neill Rose (1860-1940) of Philadelphia, Pennsylvania in 1883. Ms. Rose, born 23 October, 1860 in Washington, D.C., was the child of William John Rose and Mary Lee Mahon. She attended Mrs. Sutton's School for Girls. Their children include authors Laura Benét, William Rose Benét, and Stephen Vincent Benét.
Laura Benét (1884-1979) was educated at the Emma Willard School in Troy, New York, and at Vassar and Moravian colleges. She worked at the Spring Street Settlement in New York City from 1915 to 1917 and at the American Red Cross in Augusta, Georgia from 1917 to 1919. She later took on editorial and free-lance writing assignments. She was the author of several poetry collections, fiction, and biographical works.
William Rose Benét (1886-1950) was educated at Albany Academy and Yale College (1903-1907). After college, Benét worked for Century Magazine as a reader. He served in the U.S. Air Services during the First World War, and after the war took work as a copy writer for an advertising firm. In 1920, Henry Seidel Canby brought Benét on as an assistant editor at the New York Evening Post and in 1923, Canby, Benét, and their fellow editors left the Post to form the Saturday Review.
William Rose Benét was the author of several collections of poetry, a novel, and a collection of essays. His autobiography in verse, The Dust Which Is God (1941), was awarded a Pulitzer Prize in 1942. In addition to his long-standing (1923-1950) position with the Saturday Review, Benét contributed to several compilations of English-language poetry and literature.
William Rose Benét married four times, to: Teresa Frances Thomson (1912-1919), with whom he had three children, James Walker Benét (1914-2012), Kathleen Anne (Benét) Fry, and Frances Rosemary (Benét) Dawson; poet Elinor Wylie (1923-1928); actress Lora Baxter (1932-1937); and children's book author Majorie Flack (1941-1950).
Stephen Vincent Benét (1898-1943), educated at Summerville Academy and Yale College (1915-1919), was a well known and widely read author in the United States during the 1930s and 1940s. After the success of his long poem, John Brown's Body (1928), for which he was awarded a Pulitzer Prize in 1929, he regularly published poems, short stories, and other work in popular magazines such as The Atlantic Monthly, The New Yorker, and The Saturday Evening Post. His short story, "The Devil and Daniel Webster" (1936) was awarded the O. Henry Memorial Award in 1937. In addition to poetry and short stories, he is the author of novels, book reviews, essays, radio and stage plays, screenplays, and speeches.
Stephen Vincent Benét and Rosemary Carr married in 1921. They had three children, Thomas, Stephanie Jane, and Rachel.
Biographical information taken from Arlington National Cemetary website and other sources.
Scope and Contents
The Benét family collection consists of correspondence, writings, and other material documenting personal and professional activities of members of the literary Benét family. The collection features material by and relating to William Rose Benét and Stephen Vincent Benét.
Noteworthy correspondence files for Stephen Vincent Benét can be found with Yale College classmates Shreve Cowles Badger and John Chipman Farrar, with the literary agency Brandt & Brandt, for which there are approximately 227 pieces of correspondence, and with publishers Doubleday, Doran & Company and Farrar & Rinehart.
Larger correspondence files for William Rose Benét can be found with his third wife, Lora Baxter, the poets Jeremy Ingalls and Starr Nelson, and the Saturday Review. There are approximately 92 pieces of correspondence from Benét to Baxter, and the Starr Nelson gift consists of six scrapbooks containing approximately 360 letters between Nelson and Benét, as well as photographs, drafts or fair copies of writings, clippings, and printed ephemera.
The two largest groups of manuscript writings for Stephen Vincent Benét can be found in the Farrar & Rinehart Gift, which includes approximately 200 reader reports, and in the Material from Other Sources series, which includes drafts and printed versions of several works. For example, there are drafts of the poetry collection, Songs of Dear Old Yale, and a musical score, "The Headless Horseman," done in collaboration with Douglas Moore.
Drafts of poems and other writings by William Rose Benét can be found in the Reese Baxter and Wallace G. Fiske gifts. Other writings in the collection include a draft, typescript and autograph manuscript, of an autobiography by Colonel James Walker Benét.
Arrangement
Organized into nine series: I. Shreve Cowles Badger Gifts, 1918-1944. II. Reese Baxter Gift, 1932-1958. III. Brandt & Brandt Gift, 1930-1943. IV. John Chipman Farrar Gifts, 1918-1960. V. Farrar & Rinehart Gift, 1933-1957. VI. Wallace G. Fiske Gift, 1914-1959. VII. Henry R. Hallowell Gifts, 1920-1958. VIII. Starr Nelson Gift, 1942-1950. IX. Material from Other Sources, 1912-1979.
Related Materials
Material by or relating to the Benét family acquired by the library from family sources is located in the Benét Family Papers (YCAL MSS 1107). Additional material by or relating to Stephen Vincent and Rosemary Benét can be found in the Stephen Vincent Benét and Rosemary Benét Papers (YCAL MSS 1046). Additional material by or relating to William Rose Benét can be found in the William Rose Benét Papers (YCAL MSS 1100).
American literature -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Authors and publishers -- United States; Editors -- United States -- 20th Century -- Archives; Poets, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Publishers and publishing; Photographic prints; Authors -- United States -- 20th Century; Poets -- United States -- 20th Century; Badger, Shreve Cowles; Benét, James, 1914-; Benét, Laura; Benét, Rosemary, 1900-1962; Benét, S. V. (Stephen Vincent), 1827-1895; Benét, Stephen Vincent, 1898-1943; Benét, William Rose, 1886-1950; Farrar, John Chipman, 1896-1974; Ingalls, Jeremy, 1911-2000; Lalone, Emerson Hugh; Nelson, Starr; Wylie, Elinor, 1885-1928; Benét Family; Brandt & Brandt; Doubleday, Doran & Company; Farrar & Rinehart; Yale University. Alumni
- Shreve Cowles Badger Gift, 1918-1944; 0.21; 1 box
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Gift of Shreve Cowles Badger, 1944.
  Arrangement
  Organized into two subseries: Correspondence and Writings.
  Scope and Contents
  The Shreve Cowles Badger gift contains correspondence to Badger from members of the Benét family and others and writings by and about Stephen Vincent Benét. Correspondence features 30 pieces of correspondence to Badger from Stephen Vincent Benét, a Yale College classmate.
  - Correspondence
    - Babb, James T. (James Tinkham), 1944 July (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Benét, Frances Rose, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Benét, Laura, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Benét, Rosemary, 1921-1943, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Benét, Stephen Vincent, 1918-1943, undated (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
    - Benét, William Rose, 1921 December 2 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Carter, John Franklin, 1917–1933 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Lambert, Samuel W., 1943 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Life, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - MacLeish, Archibald, 1943 November 12 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Scott, Arthur P., 1921 December 31 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Writings
    - Badger, Shreve Cowles
      - "Stephen Vincent Benét and His Yale Contemporaries," essay, draft, typescript carbon, corrected, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Benét, Stephen Vincent
      - "The Proud Huntsmen," poem, printed version, Parabalou, [1920?] (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - "The Veteran," poem, draft, typescript carbon, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Reese Baxter Gift, 1932-1958; 0.63; 2 boxes
  Gift of Reese Baxter, 1990.
  Organized into three subseries: Correspondence, Writings, and Other Material.
  The Reese Baxter gift contains correspondece, writings, and other material relating chiefly to William Rose Benét and Lora Baxter. Benét and Baxter were married from 1932 until 1937, and the group features approximately 92 pieces of correspondence from Benét to Baxter dating from 1932 until the year of his death, 1950. There are drafts and printed versions of poems by Benét and, among other materials, there is a copy of Benét's last will and testament.
  - Correspondence
    - Amisano, Dorothy to Mr. Malicoat, 1956 February 18 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Baxter, Lora to Dorothy Amisano, 1948-1953, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Benét, William Rose to Dorothy Amisano, 1938-1950, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Benét, William Rose to Lora Baxter, 1932-1950, undated (Box 2, Folder 19-24)
    - Benét, William Rose to Mrs. Hugh Bullock, 1936 March 19 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Mitchell, Alice (Baxter) to Lora Baxter, 1948-1954, undated (Box 2, Folder 26-27)
    - Wescott, Glenway to Mrs. Benét, 1950 June 8 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Others, 1948-1958, undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Writings
    - Writings of Lora Baxter
      - "The Personal Touch," story, draft, typescript carbon, undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
      - "What Is It?" poem, draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Writings of William Rose Benét
      - Poems, drafts, typescript and autograph manuscript, and printed versions, 1932-1947, undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Writings of Others
      - Nelson, Starr
        - "In the Boulder on the Shore," tribute, typescript carbon, 1950 October 10 (Box 2, Folder 33)
      - Salomon, Isidor Lawrence
        - "W.R.B. (1886-1950)," poem, typescript, inscribed, 1950 May 11 (Box 2, Folder 34)
      - Unidentified
        - Poems, drafts, typescript and autograph manuscript, undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
        - Unidentified, undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Other Material
    - Cancelled check, 1952 December 12 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Clippings, 1932-1957, undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Clippings, 1932-1955, undated (Box 21 (Oversize), Folder 273)
    - Drawings, 1933, undated (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Invitation list, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Legal documents, 1937–1955 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Manuscript notes, undated (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Printed material, 1943-1951, undated (Box 3, Folder 43-44)
- Brandt & Brandt Gift, 1930-1943; 0.21; 1 box
  Gift of Brandt & Brandt, 1955.
  Arranged chronologically.
  The Brandt & Brandt gift consists of the literary agency's correspondence file for Stephen Vincent Benét for the period from 1930 through 1943. There are approximately 227 pieces of correspondence from Benét to various representatives of the firm, including many to founder Carl Brandt. Letters concern literary and personal topics, with many relating to stories and articles for publication.
  - Correspondence, 1930-1943, undated (Box 4, Folder 45-50)
- John Chipman Farrar Gifts, 1918-1960; 0.21; 1 box
  Gifts of John Chipman Farrar, 1941-1960.
  Correspondence, writings, and printed material relating to Stephen Vincent Benét assembled by Yale college classmate, and publisher, John Chipman Farrar.
  - Correspondence
    - Benét, Stephen Vincent, 1918-1942, undated (Box 5, Folder 51-52)
    - Engel, Gabriel, 1946 January 11 (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - Yale University. Library, 1941 April 24 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Writings
    - Benét, Stephen Vincent
      - "Listen to the People," printed version, circa 1941 (Box 21 (Oversize), Folder 274)
    - Chamberlain, John
      - "The New Books," review of Western Star by Stephen Vincent Benét, proof, corrected, [1943] June (Box 5, Folder 55)
      - "The New Books," review of Western Star by Stephen Vincent Benét, proof, corrected, [1943] June (Box 21 (Oversize), Folder 275)
  - Other Material
    - Clippings, 1928–1960 (Box 5, Folder 56)
    - Printed ephemera, 1939, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 57)
- Farrar & Rinehart Gift, 1933-1957; 2.71; 7 boxes
  Gift of Farrar & Rinehart, 195[?].
  Organized into two subseries: Correspondence and Other Material.
  The Farrar & Rinehart gift comprises the publisher's files for Stephen Vincent Benét. There are general correspondence files for Rosemary and Stephen Vincent Benét containing original letters, carbons of letters from Farrar & Rinehart, and third party correspondence with other publishers and the literary agency Brandt & Brandt. There are also files relating to a memorial, permissions, publicity, and individual works by Benét.
  Other material features approximately 200 reader reports written by Benét on different titles. This group of material would appear to represent what amounts to Benét's unpublished literary criticism. Reports, typewritten, vary in length from a few lines to several pages. Most reports are written in an epistolary style, addressed to John Farrar or others in the firm. In reports, Benét highlights or criticizes aspects of the work, offers his opinion on whether or not Farrar & Rinehart should publish the work, and sometimes either identifies areas needing attention or offers advice to authors on how to move forward.
  - Correspondence
    - General Correspondence
      - Benét, Rosemary, 1936-1947, undated (Box 6, Folder 58-59)
      - Benét, Stephen Vincent, 1934–1945 (Box 6, Folder 60-69)
      - Material removed from Benét, Stephen Vincent, 1942, [1944?] (Box 21 (Oversize), Folder 276)
      - Benét, Stephen Vincent, 1945-1957, undated (Box 7, Folder 70-73)
      - "Memorial folder", 1943, undated (Box 7, Folder 74-78)
      - "Permissions", 1937-1955, undated (Box 7, Folder 79)
      - "Promotion booklet", 1943-1944, undated (Box 7, Folder 80-82)
    - By Title
      - America, 1943-1956, undated (Box 8, Folder 83-85)
      - The Beginning of Wisdom, 1948 October 28 (Box 8, Folder 86)
      - "Biography", 1948-1949, undated (Box 8, Folder 87)
      - A Book of Americans, 1933-1957, undated (Box 8, Folder 88-92)
      - Burning City, 1934-1937, undated (Box 8, Folder 93)
      - "A Child Is Born", 1942-1946, undated (Box 8, Folder 94)
      - "Companion to ' A Book of Americans ' (Never Published)", 1934 (Box 8, Folder 95)
      - Dear Adolf, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 96)
      - The Devil and Daniel Webster, 1937-1956, undated (Box 9, Folder 97-98)
      - "The Devil and Daniel Webster" libretto, 1939-1953, undated (Box 9, Folder 99)
      - James Shore's Daughter, 1935–1937 (Box 9, Folder 100)
      - John Brown's Body, 1933-1957, undated (Box 9, Folder 101-103)
      - Clipping removed from John Brown's Body, undated (Box 21 (Oversize), Folder 277)
      - John Brown's Body revised edition, 1954-1956, undated (Box 9, Folder 104)
      - Johnny Pye and the Fool-killer, 1938-1939, undated (Box 9, Folder 105)
      - "Listen to the People", 1941-1954, undated (Box 9, Folder 106-107)
      - "Nightmare at Noon", 1940-1941, undated (Box 9, Folder 108)
      - "Poetry Anthology (Never Published)", 1939-1940, undated (Box 9, Folder 109)
      - "The Power and the Land", 1940-1943, undated (Box 10, Folder 110)
      - The Selected Works of Stephen Vincent Benét, 1938-1955, undated (Box 10, Folder 111-112)
      - The Selected Works of Stephen Vincent Benét copyright information, 1941-1955, undated (Box 10, Folder 113-114)
      - "Sing a Song of Americans", 1942–1946 (Box 10, Folder 115)
      - Tales Before Midnight, 1939-1942, undated (Box 10, Folder 116)
      - They Burned the Books, 1942-1943, undated (Box 10, Folder 117-118)
      - Thirteen O'Clock, 1937–1945 (Box 10, Folder 119)
      - We Stand United, and Other Radio Scripts, 1941-1957, undated (Box 10, Folder 120)
      - Western Star, 1934-1956, undated (Box 10, Folder 121-122)
      - Young Adventure, 1945 (Box 10, Folder 123)
      - Zero Hour, 1940-1941, undated (Box 11, Folder 124-127)
  - Other Material
    - Radio scripts, undated (Box 11, Folder 128)
    - Reader reports, 1936-1943, undated (Box 11, Folder 129-138)
    - Reader reports, 1940-1942, undated (Box 12, Folder 139-140)
    - "Speeches", 1942, undated (Box 12, Folder 141)
    - Other work, undated (Box 12, Folder 142)
- Wallace G. Fiske Gift, 1914-1959; 0.42; 1 box
  Gift of Wallace G. Fiske, 1957date unknown.
  The Fiske gift contains material relating to the Benét family, and William Rose Benét in particular, assembled by the Reverend Emerson Hugh Lalone. Correspondence includes subdivisions for letters to Lalone and to William Rose Benét. There are several pieces of writing by Benét, including corrected typescript drafts of a possible story, "Gowden Elspie," and article, "Night Thoughts of a Goldsmith." Miscellaneous other material, such as biographical information, clippings, and photographs, relate chiefly to William Rose Benét.
  - Correspondence
    - Emerson Hugh Lalone Correspondence
      - Benét, James, 1914-, 1957 March 28 (Box 13, Folder 143)
      - Benét, Laura, 1957 (Box 13, Folder 144)
      - Benét, William Rose, 1949-1950, undated (Box 13, Folder 145)
      - Cady, Harrison, 1957 April (Box 13, Folder 146)
      - Coe, Lloyd, 1940 July 24 (Box 13, Folder 147)
        Includes letter to Coe William Rose Benét and material relating to The Dust Which Is God
      - Fry, George Blanchard, Mrs., 1957 April 16 (Box 13, Folder 148)
      - Pearson, Norman Holmes, 1956-1958, undated (Box 13, Folder 149)
      - Smythe, Daniel, 1957 (Box 13, Folder 150)
      - St. Lawrence University. Library, 1957 (Box 13, Folder 151)
      - Yale University. Library, 1957 (Box 13, Folder 152)
    - William Rose Benét Correspondence
      - Canby, Henry Seidel, 1943 September 17 (Box 13, Folder 153)
      - Eaton, Walter Prichard, 1920 January 12 (Box 13, Folder 154)
      - Flanner, Hildegaarde, 1932 June 16 (Box 13, Folder 155)
      - Foley, John L., 1942 July 12 (Box 13, Folder 156)
      - Fry, Kathleen Anne (Benét), 1941 January 13 (Box 13, Folder 157)
      - Hobson, Dorothy, 1942 July 16 (Box 13, Folder 158)
      - Pratt, E. J., 1948 November 17 (Box 13, Folder 159)
      - Saturday Review, 1951 [October?] (Box 13, Folder 160)
      - Sutton, E. F. (Edward Forrester), 1914 July 27 (Box 13, Folder 161)
      - Updegraff, Allan, 1915 January 28 (Box 13, Folder 162)
      - Others, 1931-1948, undated (Box 13, Folder 163)
      - Copies of letters to others, undated (Box 13, Folder 164-165)
    - Other Correspondence
      - Others, 1950-1958, undated (Box 13, Folder 166)
  - Writings
    - Writings by William Rose Benét
      - "[Gowden?] Elspie," draft, typescript carbon, corrected, undated (Box 13, Folder 167)
      - "Maurois, Andre: Aspect of Biography," [lecture?] notes, typescript, circa 1928 (Box 13, Folder 168)
      - "Night Thoughts of a Goldsmith," draft, typescript carbon, corrected, undated (Box 13, Folder 169)
      - "Pan and the Children," poem, typescript carbon, corrected, undated (Box 13, Folder 170)
      - "Reviewing Ten Years: A Personal Record of The Saturday Review of Literature ," essay, printed version, undated (Box 13, Folder 171)
      - "Summa," poem, typescript, signed, undated (Box 13, Folder 172)
    - Writings of Others
      - Cousins, Norman
        - "Don't Resign from the Human Race," essay, printed version, Saturday Review of Literature, 1948 August 7 (Box 13, Folder 173)
      - Henderson, Archibald
        - "Mathematics and the Physical Sciences," essay, printed version, signed, undated (Box 13, Folder 174)
      - Hillyer, Robert
        - "Poetry's New Priesthood," article, printed version, Saturday Review of Literature, 1949 June 18 (Box 13, Folder 175)
      - Lampson, Oliver Locker
        - "Frederick Locker Lampson," essay, printed version, undated (Box 13, Folder 176)
      - Lowell, Amy
        - "Walt Whitman and the New Poetry," essay, printed version, The Yale Review, undated (Box 13, Folder 177)
      - Nelson, Starr
        - "In the Boulder on the Shore," tribute, typescript, signed, 1950 October 10 (Box 13, Folder 178)
  - Other Material
    - Addresses, undated (Box 13, Folder 179)
    - Bibliographical information, undated (Box 13, Folder 180)
    - Biographical information, undated (Box 13, Folder 181)
    - Certificate, 1945 January 18 (Box 13, Folder 182)
    - Clippings, 1922-1948, undated (Box 13, Folder 183)
    - Clippings, 1918-1942, undated (Box 21 (Oversize), Folder 278)
    - Empty envelope, undated (Box 13, Folder 184)
    - Genealogical information, undated (Box 13, Folder 185)
    - Manuscript notes, undated (Box 13, Folder 186)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 13, Folder 187)
    - Printed material, 1934-1959, undated (Box 13, Folder 188-190)
    - Quotes, undated (Box 13, Folder 191)
    - Scrapbook page, 1914, undated (Box 13, Folder 192)
- Henry R. Hallowell Gifts, 1920-1958; 0.21; 1 box
  Gifts of Henry R. Hallowell, 1979.
  The Hallowell gifts contains a small amount of material relating to Stephen Vincent Benét.
  - Correspondence
    - Benét, Stephen Vincent, 1928-[1936?] (Box 14, Folder 193)
    - Fenton, Charles A., 1958 July (Box 14, Folder 194)
    - House of Books, Ltd., 1939-1944, undated (Box 14, Folder 195)
    - Empty envelope, 1943 April 21 (Box 14, Folder 196)
  - Other Material
    - Printed ephemera, 1920–1939 (Box 14, Folder 197)
    - Receipts, 1939–1945 (Box 14, Folder 198)
- Starr Nelson Gift, 1942-1950; 1.04; 3 boxes
  Gift of Starr Nelson, date unknown.
  The Starr Nelson gift features six scrapbooks ("volumes") containing correspondence between Nelson and William Rose Benét. Correspondence, including approximately 360 original letters between Nelson and Benét, is arranged in chonological order from 1942 until 1950. Volumes also contain photographs, drafts or fair copies of writings, clippings, and printed ephemera.